<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The wars of David, and the peaceable reign of Solomon symbolizing the times of warfare and refreshment of the saints of the most high God, to whom a priestly kingdom is shortly to be given, after the order of Melchisedeck. Set forth in two treatises written by J. Lead: and according to divine ordination publish'd in this present year of jubilee. For the service of all the children of the captivity, now watching and praying in many countries, for the great jubilee of the Lord to begin, and follow upon this very speedily. Containing I. An alarm to the holy warriours to fight the battels of the Lamb. II. The glory of Sharon, in the renovation of nature, introducing the kingdom of Christ in his sealed virgins, redeemed from the earth.</title>
            <author>Lead, Jane, 1623-1704.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 445 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 102 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A88859</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L791A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R226473</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99899616</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99899616</idno>
            <idno type="VID">154251</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A88859)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 154251)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2407:14a)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The wars of David, and the peaceable reign of Solomon symbolizing the times of warfare and refreshment of the saints of the most high God, to whom a priestly kingdom is shortly to be given, after the order of Melchisedeck. Set forth in two treatises written by J. Lead: and according to divine ordination publish'd in this present year of jubilee. For the service of all the children of the captivity, now watching and praying in many countries, for the great jubilee of the Lord to begin, and follow upon this very speedily. Containing I. An alarm to the holy warriours to fight the battels of the Lamb. II. The glory of Sharon, in the renovation of nature, introducing the kingdom of Christ in his sealed virgins, redeemed from the earth.</title>
                  <author>Lead, Jane, 1623-1704.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16]+ p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by J. Bradford, in Little Britain,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Bound and filmed with "The Christian warfare" (Wing L27A).</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: lacks all after page [16].</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Christian literature --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Korey Jackson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>Korey Jackson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:3"/>
            <p>THE <hi>Wars of <hi>David,</hi>
               </hi> AND THE PEACEABLE <hi>Reign of <hi>Solomon,</hi>
               </hi> Symbolizing the TIMES Of Warfare and Refreſhment of the Saints of the Moſt High GOD, To whom a Prieſtly Kingdom is ſhortly to be given, after the Order of <hi>MELCHISEDECK.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Set forth in Two Treatiſes Written by <hi>J. LEAD:</hi> and according to Divine Ordination Publiſh'd in this preſent Year of JUBILEE.</p>
            <p>For the Service of all the Children of the Captivity, now Watching and Praying in many Countries, for the Great Jubilee of the LORD to begin, and follow upon This very Speedily.</p>
            <p>CONTAINING
<list>
                  <item>I. An Alarm to the Holy Warriours to Fight the Battels of the <hi>LAMB.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>II. The Glory of <hi>Sharon,</hi> in the Renovation of Nature, introducing the Kingdom of <hi>Chriſt</hi> in his Sealed Virgins, Redeemed from the Earth.</item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Dan. vii. 28.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>—Hitherto is the End of the Matter.</p>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>J. Bradford,</hi> in <hi>Little Britain,</hi> 1700.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="preface">
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:4"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:4"/>
            <head>The PREFACE Of the Publiſher.</head>
            <p>THE Treatment which the former Books of this Author, for the ſpace now of about Twenty Years ſince they began here to Appear, have met with from her own Native Country, is ſuch; as might be enough indeed to diſcourage any New Attempt of this Nature, and might have prevented the ſending abroad in theſe Kingdoms, the two following Divine and Myſtical Treatiſes; ſo that they were like to have been the Portion only of thoſe Foreign Nations, that deſire them not a little, and know how to value them: had there not been the Interven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Hand of Providence, in a manner very Extraordinary to command them forth at this Time, with a ſpecial Excitement of the Holy Spirit, to blow the Trumpet yet louder and louder, and to try this Adulterous Nation once more, whether they will hear, or whether they will refuſe.</p>
            <p>Whatever Siniſter Suſpicions we may before have of any one, when they lie upon their Death-Bed, we are willing to hear what they have to ſay for or againſt themſelves. The <hi>Wills</hi> not only of the Good, but even of Flagitions Livers are regarded, and thought to have ſomewhat Sacred: And the Dying Speeches of the Worſt of Criminals, ſuch as have utterly Shipwreck'd their Credit, are not altogether ſlighted, but are looked into, and ſearch'd after. How much more then ought we to look into, and ſearch after, and have an eſteem for the Dying Declarati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons (and eſpecially if they be more than ordinary) of Perſons that have been any whit Singular and Eminent in their Lives, by having made a good Profeſſion before God and Man, againſt the general Stream and Torrent of the World? But if moreover the Finger of GOD ſhall ſhew it ſelf, to give an Honour to what is by them Declared, will it not ſtill be the more reaſonable for us to make a Sober and Impartial Inquiry into the Subject of it? Now upon theſe Conſiderations What is here preſented to the Publick, may juſtly claim a ſerious Scrutiny, and a fair Examination from all manner of Perſons: who cannot but have their Intereſt herein,
<pb facs="tcp:154251:5"/>if what is ſaid be true; and if it be falſe, to detect it. For though the Author (Bleſſed be God) be yet living, (being now Aged Seventy Seven Years) this will not in the leaſt derogate from the Authority of what is here Delivered from her Mouth, and Written down with all Faithfulneſs; as if the ſame were not to have the value of a Dying De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration to all intents and purpoſes. Nay it ought to be greater; for as much as it has pleaſed the Mighty Conquerer over Death, whoſe Name is called <hi>THE WORD OF GOD,</hi> to exert his Power upon this occaſion, in reſtoring and reviving That which drew near to Corruption, and in bringing up from the Gates of the Grave: that it might be for a Memorial of his Glory and Praiſe, and for an Encouragement to many, unto whom this ſhall come, that they may Believe, and be Obedient to the <hi>Call</hi> that is now ſounding in many (yea Moſt) parts of Europe, and is not heard only in a Corner.</p>
            <p>Now whereas there are ſeveral Things in the <hi>Journals,</hi> and in <hi>Other</hi> Writings of this Author, before Publiſhed, that have given Offence to ſome Perſons of Sincere Intentions, and Lovers of the Truth, yet not ſet quite free from the Traditions of Men; She was pleaſed to De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare to them that were about her in the time of her Sickneſs, and in the greateſt Extremity of it, that though ſhe knew her ſelf to be an unworthy Inſtrument, taken up by GOD out of his free and abound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Grace, yet ſhe had endeavour'd (to her utmost,) to be faithful to the Gift committed to her, and to diſcharge her Truſt, in delivering what ſhe had received; which ſhe did not doubt but he would Vindicate, and go on to Bleſs, as he had begun to Bleſs already in ſeveral Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions: And that ſhe was certainly aſſured, by the Teſtimony of JES<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>S her Lord, that the Work which was in this Kingdom begun (howſoever contemptible it did generally appear) ſhould never be ſtop'd, but ſhould prevail againſt all manner of Oppoſitions, till his Holy and Peaceable Reign ſhould be Here fully Eſtabliſhed, according to all what ſhe had had a Proſpect of in the Spirit, and what had been ſet forth for a publick Good, if not in this, yet in the approaching Age. Many ſweet Admo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nitions at the ſame Time, and Encouragements to Perſeverance, without ſhewing the leaſt Heſitation or Doubt all the while, came from her with much Power: And ſhe expreſſed the greateſt Satisfaction to put off her Vile Tabernacle, and to be with the Lord; deſiring to be diſſolved for this End, and ſo to go to her Predeceſſors in the Faith, unleſs he had ſome further Work to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ill and command her.</p>
            <p>In conſideration of which, there can be no Legitimate Prejudice againſt
<pb facs="tcp:154251:5"/>the Sincerity of the Witneſs, or the Validity of the Teſtimony laid down in the following Papers: And all the Eſteem that is uſually pay'd to the moſt Solemn and ev'n Dying Words of Perſons of the ſtricteſt Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bity, is due to theſe. The Books of this Writer are (for the moſt part) to be ſimply look'd on as Narrations, and the value of them doth not depend upon any other Qualifications, but upon the Credibility of the Relator. Now greater Proofs cannot be given of the Integrity of a Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, than what is here to be found; there being ſo little Artifice us'd to Put upon the World, as all her Methods have been moſt ſtrangely con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to thoſe of the World: of which numerous Inſtances of her Life might be given. Neither as to the Ability or Capacity of any Perſon, in or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to be a Witneſs in ſuch Caſes, are there more favourable Preſump<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions to be found. She has had a long Experience; has ſeen the Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>carriages of many; has liv'd in much Watchfulneſs and Prayer Day and Night, all the Years of her Widdow-hood, ſince the Year <hi>1671;</hi> has had a longer Courſe of Obſervations, than would be enough to make one Excellent in the moſt d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>fficult and crabbed Sciences, where there is but a Diſpoſition in Nature; has kept as it were a Calendar of theſe Obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervations, and from Year to Year did make her Calculations from the ſame, at the beginning of every New Year, ſo long as ſhe had her Eye<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſight; has been almost continually exercis'd under great Temptations and Oppoſitions, and been Fighting the <hi>Good Fight of Faith</hi> from her youth upwards; has been above Threeſcore Years call'd by GOD, after a manner more than ordinary, and to her ſelf exceeding Strange, as well as to others, unto a Life which the World knows not, and cannot Judge of; and has been above half the time under the more immediate and constant Viſitations of the <hi>Spirit of Wiſdom and Revelation,</hi> as what hath been already Publiſh'd doth Testifie. And 'tis to be obſerv'd that though ſhe was Baptized, and Educated in the Church of <hi>England,</hi> in which all the Extraordinary Stirrings of the Divine Spirit are too generally Slighted, and by ſome Blaſphemed, it pleaſed the Wiſdom of GOD more Illuſtriouſly to break forth in the manner of her Conver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, in the Sixteenth Year of her Age: and ſo to give an Evidence that the Voice of the Eternal Wo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d of God, ſpeaking to Souls in a diſtinct and ſenſible manner, is Real and Subſtantial, not Imaginary; being to be diſtinguiſhed by ſuch, who can't be ſuppos'd to have had any pre-con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived Notions about it, but muſt have the Prejudices of Education di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectly againſt it, and all External Motives not to attend to it. The Sober and Moral Converſation in which ſhe was Nurtur'd, was not ſufficient to give her any Reſt, when this Voice firſt ſpake to her: which was very
<pb facs="tcp:154251:6"/>ſuddenly and ſurprizingly. For it was in a time of great Feſtivity, at the Celebration of the Nativity of CHRIST (according to cuſtom) with Muſick and Dancing, in the Houſe of her Father, where was a Concourſe for that end of the Gentry; when of a ſudden grievious Sor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row was darted as Fire into her Bowels, and ſhe was made to conſider that this was not the way to be Comform'd to CHRIST, or to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>member his Birth aright; And a ſoft Whiſper gently entred into her, ſaying, <hi>Ceaſe from this, I have another Dance to lead thee in; for this is Vanity.</hi> 
               <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pon which ſhe was as conſtrain'd to give over abruptly her Dancing, and ſo preſently withdrew her ſelf from the Company, retiring to conſider of this <hi>Immediate Call.</hi> Which the Divine Spirit purſued ſo very hard, as after this ſhe had no liberty to Converſe, as formerly in the Family, or to mind any concern of it: but was ſo wholly taken up in the conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration of her Interiour State, and of the One <hi>Thing neceſſary,</hi> as to deſert all things beſides. Yet though her Relations and Acquaintance took great notice, and marvelled much at what had happen'd, ſhe dili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gently conceal'd the true Cauſe from them all; excepting only a Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lain in the Houſe, who having ſome time afterward ſurpriz'd her read<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in his Study, inquired into the matter, bad her be of good Courage, and believe that God had ſome great Good to bring about, by all this Conflict of Soul ſhe was in. Which was ſo terrible indeed, as nothing was able to give her any Satisfaction or Reſt, or to eaſe her Wounded Spirit, that was ſtruck through and through, for having once perſiſted in a falſehood about a Triffle: The Senſe of which continued upon her for the ſpace of Three Years, with very great Anguiſh and Trouble; theſe Words being frequently brought before her, <hi>Whoever loveth and mak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth a Lye cannot enter into the</hi> New Jeruſalem. The Dreadfulneſs and Horrour of Sin carried her down to the Gates of Hell: and every little Circumſtance of its Evil, was continually preſented to her Mind, with all the poſſible Agnravations thereof. And if this were but her be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning, what may we expect of her latter End? And if in the firſt Converſion only of a Soul to GOD, ſo great a Dread there be, for having offended againſt the Truth in but a <hi>Trivial</hi> matter, how great of neceſſity muſt it be in the Progreſs of that Soul (if it ſhould fall again ſo ſtrangely) to offend against the Truth more Highly, more Solemnly, and in matters of the very greatest Importance? Surely this is no flight Preſumption for the Vadility of a Teſtimony, which is given after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward in the moſt Sacred Form, and perſiſted in with the greateſt conſtancy and chearfulneſs, notwithſtanding all kind of Oppoſitions from the World
<pb facs="tcp:154251:6"/>and the Devil, as well as the Fleſh. Now it was in the Nineteenth Year of her Age, when the Light of the Divine Countenance, which had been hither to hid, begun to ſhine upon her, and to bring her Soul out of this State of Obſcurity and Darkneſs, and out of the Pains of Hell, that had taken hold upon her, feeling the Arrows of the Wrath of the Almighty: And ſhe was Comforted with the ſweet Meſſage of the Free and Super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abounding Love and Grace of the moſt Tender and Merciful Father; and was ſo richly favoured by her dear and bleſſed Mediator, as to receive at that time the Seal of her Abſolution and Aſſurance, in a manner very ſpecial, there being preſented to her in a Viſion, the form of a Pardon, with a Seal to it; ſignifying that her Tranſgreſſions were blotted out, and that ſhe was Sealed by the <hi>Spirit,</hi> for the Promiſe of the Father; as a Witneſs whereof a mighty Guſt and Power of Prayer was then given to her. And ever ſince ſhe has been a trained Soldier, under the Diſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pline of the Bleſſed JES<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>S, and the leadings of his Spirit: which is a Spirit trying the Reins and the Marrow, and that will not abide but with ſimplicity of Heart, and Truth in the inward Parts. Let this ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice for the Credibility of the Evidence: for the preſent at leaſt.</p>
            <p>Now as for the Subject Matter both of the one and the other Treatiſe, it is a Divine Call to prepare and fit our ſelves againſt the greateſt Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>volution to come upon the World, that ever has been, with Directions how we ought to behave our ſelves in this wonderful Criſis, and what ſhall be the Succeſs if we abide Faithful and Stedfaſt? The ſtile and manner, in which they are written, is not ſuitable to the Genius of this Polite Age, and eſpecially of this Nation: It is Parabolical and Emblema<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tical, full of Figurative Speeches, and Abrupt Tranſitions, and ſo utter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſtrange to the Mordern Reformation of Language from the Stage, as it is not to be wondred at that it pleaſes ſo few; but withal ſuch as it is the Power of God is the more manifeſted through it, and it wants not alſo a Beauty and Strength which is peculiar to it, and which would be very hard (if poſſible) to imitate.</p>
            <p>In the firſt Treatiſe there are theſe Things Remarkable, <hi>viz</hi> the Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral of the Army appearing upon a White Horſe, in a Triumphant Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner; the Trials, Excuſes, Expoſtulations, and Diſcipline of the Perſon to whom he ſo appears; the Parable of the Mill, which is to ſupply the Army; the Decree of the Heavenly Council, and Proclamation of War; the Alarm for the Gathering of a Prieſtly Hoſt: How they are to be Admitted into the Military Roll; that this is already open'd in Heaven; the Time, Place, and Perſons for the Rendezvous; an Obſervation upon the Continuance and Succeſs of this War; all the Soldiers enter into pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent
<pb facs="tcp:154251:7"/>Pay; all that Conquer are to win a Crown; how they are diſpos'd of that Dye in Battel, before their Warfare is accompliſh'd; the Reſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection of the Spirit of <hi>Deborah,</hi> and Prophecying in the Army; the Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery of <hi>Paradiſe,</hi> for the Recovery of which the War is undertaken; the Heavenly Auxiliaries; the Aſſurance of Victory; the Intereſt of all Parties to join thomſelves with this Army, a Deſcription of the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>xiliaries riding on White Mules, with Cenſersin their Hands: and the effect of their Appearance; being the firſt Pitched Battel. After this follows another <hi>Alarm</hi> to Battel; a Proſpect and Promiſe of greater Conqueſts; the Diſcovery of the <hi>New Jeruſalem,</hi> and repeated Encouragements to Fight for it; a Letter from the King of this City to the Army; the Counter-plotting of the Enemy; the Communication of the Two <hi>Jeruſalems;</hi> the Allegory of <hi>Eſther</hi> and <hi>Mordecai,</hi> and the wonderful ſucceſs of the Children of <hi>Wiſdom;</hi> how they are aſſiſted by the Four and Twenty Throne-Elders; a Gracious Encouragement to Perſeverance; how they are viſited by an Heavenly Hoſt, and from then receive Anointed Shields; the Three Watches, and the great Power that is given in the Third; ſome particular Inſtructions to the Soldiers and Watchmen; the Miraculous manner of the Increaſe of this Holy Army; the Spies to this Army, the Seven Spirits of the Lamb; his Mark and Seal; the Proclamation of the Jubilee; the Watch-word; Counſels and Cautions to them that would ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain the Benefit of it; the Magical Rod of <hi>Moſes,</hi> needful to the great approaching Deliverance of the Captives; the due Preparation of the Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives, in order to partake of the Promiſed Jubilee; the Bleſſing upon them; a Threefold Appeal, concerning the Premiſes, to <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nbelievers, to Half-Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lievers, and to Believers.</p>
            <p>In the other Treatiſe are to be obſerv'd the many and wonderful Rewards of the Conquerors; the Mighty Powers of Faith; the Bleſſed Fruits of Love; the Magnificent Converſation of diſtant Spirits; the Angelical Generation and Multiplication; the Manner and Progreſs of the Replant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing <hi>Paradiſe;</hi> the Separation from the Earth; the Divine Cup which is the Spring of <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nderſtanding, the Fountain of Wiſdom, and the Light of Knowledge; the Communication of the Prieſtly, Prophetical, and Royal Spirit; with an Account of the Court of the Prince of Peace, and ſome Obſervations on his Miniſters. All is Calculated with a ſpecial regard to the <hi>New Century</hi> now upon its entring: And indeed all the Writings of this Author do point at ſome great Reformation of the Church, as very near at the Door; but carried on by an Inviſible Power, and not by the Wiſdom or Arm of Fleſh. And the ſubſtance of them all, as well as of theſe two, may be reduced to the following plain Propoſitions, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:7"/>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>1. That</hi> God <hi>is no Regarder of</hi> perſons, <hi>but that whoſoever truly fears him, and ſeeks to do his Will in any Tribe, Profeſſion, or Religion, is accepted by him: and that out of all the Tribes, Profeſſions, and Religions that are at this Day over the whole World, he will gather to himſelf an Holy and Peculiar People, to be as the firſt Fruits of the Kingdom of his SON.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>2. That the Promiſe of the Father concerning the Gift of the Holy Spirit was never determin'd to Place or Time: But that it was extended Univer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fally to as many as ſhould Believe throughout all the Ages of the Church.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>3. That this Spirit Blows where it liſts, and is not controlable by the Wiſdom or Power of Man.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>4. That Regeneration in Man is the Work of the Spirit, and that Man ought only to ceaſe from the Activity of his own Will therein, and to ſeek to become wholly Paſſive to the Divine Operation.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>5. That in the proceſs of Regeneration, there is a Conformity to the Bleſſed JESUS, as to the great Exemplar: and that the ſeveral Degrees hereof are as ſo many Steps to the Kingdom of GOD.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>6. That this Kingdom conſiſts in perfect Righteouſneſs, Peace and Joy in the Holy Ghoſt: and in the Renovation of the whole Man, Spirit, Soul and Body.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>7. That this Kingdom ſhall comprehend the utmoſt Ends of the Earth, by Virtue of an Everlaſting Decree: and that Chriſt as he is the ſecond</hi> Adam, <hi>is the Head and Repreſentative of the whole Humane Nature.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>8. That not only the Juſtice, but alſo the Mercy of GOD is over all his Works: and that as the one is not confin'd to this ſhort Life, ſo alſo not the other; but that they may both endure for Ever.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>9. That CHRIST, as he is Heir of all Things, will loſe nothing that is his Right, or that the Father hath given him: And that therefore of his Kingdom there ſhall be no End, but all Creatures whether in Heaven, or in Earth, or under the Earth, ſhall be made to ſubmit themſelves to him, and to bow the Knee.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>10. That the Times of Reſtitution are Now about beginning: and that there is a Voice at preſent in the Wilderneſs, Crying,</hi> That the Kingdom of Heaven upon Earth is at hand.</item>
            </list>
            <p>And moreover it is to be remark'd, in order to a right underſtanding both of Theſe and of all ſuch Books, that they do generally turn upon theſe Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſitions: <hi>1.</hi> That beſide the Literal Senſe of the Scriptures, there is frequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly a Myſtical one alſo. <hi>2.</hi> That it is not enough to Believe the Death or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurrection of Chriſt, without bearing the Marks of them in our ſelves; And <hi>3.</hi> That the Operations of the Divine Spirit, and the Openings of the Kingdom of Chriſt, are ſucceſſive and gradual. Which being well underſtood, there will be no great difficulty found in the Reading of theſe, or any other Treatiſes of the ſame Author. This was thought neceſſary to premiſe for Caution to the Readers, that ſo they may Apply what they Read to ſome of thoſe General Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſitions, or Interpret her by one or other of theſe Principles, and be careful
<pb facs="tcp:154251:8"/>not to wreſt the ſame to their own Condemnation. For as it is very dangerous to be impos'd upon in matters of this nature, ſo is it no leſs dangerous to im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe on our ſelves, by perverting any thing from and againſt the original De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign: and more dangerous to judge Definitively in a Caſe that doth not proper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly fall under our Judicature and Cogniſance; leſt haply we may be found Figh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters against the Spirit of God, when we think it not. All that is here preſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, is virtually an Appeal to the Soveraign Judge; to whom it belongs to Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rize, or Condemn that which is ſent forth as in his Name: And he will not ſuffer Judgment to be wreſted out of his Hands. For the Work of every Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſhall ſhortly be made manifeſt: And the Day is at hand which ſhall declare it by the Revelation of Fire; wherein the Children of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom ſhall be Purified in the firſt place. And tho' there will be found among all of theſe ſome <hi>Hay</hi> and <hi>Stuble</hi> to be burnt up; yet the pretious Materials will hereby ſuffer no loſs, but will appear ſo much the more radiant; and all that is Eſtabliſh'd upon the Foundation of the Rock Chriſt (who ceaſes not ſtill to follow his true <hi>Iſrael</hi> in the Wilderneſs) ſhall abide in the Furnace, and over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come the Flames. The Conſideration of S. <hi>Ambroſe</hi> may be enough, I think, to ſtrike Terrour into us, and to teach us to be ſober in Judging: Who after ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving ſpoken of that Fiery Baptiſm, whereby all Iniquity ſhall be conſum'd, and the Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teous ſhall ſhine as the Sun in the Kingdom of their Father, ſaith, <hi>Omnes oportet pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bari, &amp;c.</hi> 
               <q>All muſt be tried by the Fire, whoever deſires to return to <hi>Paradiſe:</hi> All muſt paſs through the Flames, whether it be that <hi>John</hi> the Evangeliſt, whom the Lord ſo loved, as to ſay concerning him to <hi>Peter, If I will that he tarry till he come, what is that to thee? follow thou me.</hi> Concerning his Death ſome have doubted, concerning his Paſſage through the Fire we cannot doubt. Whether it be that <hi>Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter</hi> who receiveth the Keys of the Kingdom, he muſt alſo ſay, we have paſſed through the Fire. He is tried as Silver; I ſhall be tried as Lead: till all the Lead do vaniſh I ſhall burn. <hi>And again he ſaith:</hi> 'With Fire ſhall all the Children of <hi>Levi</hi> be Purified, with Fire ſhall <hi>Ezekiel,</hi> with Fire ſhall <hi>Daniel,</hi> &amp;c be Purified. Wo is me if my Work burn, and I ſuffer the loſs of my Labour: And if the Lord ſave his Servants, they ſhall be ſaved by Faith, yet ſo ſaved as by Fire; and if we ſhall not be burnt up, yet we ſhall be burnt. <hi>Alſo he ſaith farther:</hi> 'There is onely one, who could not feel this Fire, even he who is the Righteouſneſs of God,<hi>Chriſt.</hi>
               </q> Wherefore for as much as the Day of this fiery Trial is at hand, which hath been ſpoken of both by This, and by many others of the Antient Holy Fathers, and has been alſo mentioned in many places of the Writings of this our Author, let us every one ſeek to prepare our ſelves according to the Word of our Lord, to watch that this Day over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>take us not unawares, and to hold out in the Warfare of Faith and Love without waver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing: And eſpecially to take heed that we judge not, that we may not be judged; but that we leave judgment to whom judgment belongs, who <hi>in Righteouſneſs doth Judge and make War,</hi> and out of whoſe Mouth <hi>goeth a ſharp Sword,</hi> with which he will ſmite the Nations, and <hi>rule them with a Rod of Iron,</hi> who refuſe to ſubmit to his Golden Scepter. And it is hoped, that what is here Deliver'd, may be an excitement to ſome, yea to many, to prepare themſelves accordingly, to love the Lord <hi>Ieſus,</hi> and to believe the Promiſe of his coming; to live the <hi>Life of Faith,</hi> according to the Pattern in the Mount; and to love one another even as he hath loved us: that ſo the Beauty of the Primitive <hi>Philadelphia</hi> may break forth, and the Glory of the Apoſtolical <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> may ſhine out, in the Spirit and Name of the everlaſting Father; that all Nations may go up together to the Houſe of the Lord, and that this Nation in particular may be as the Garden of <hi>Sha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ron. Amen, Amen.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="part">
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:8"/>
            <head>A Short Exerciſe of the Spiritual Warriours, <hi>Recommended by an Old Experienc'd Soldier in the</hi> Faith, <hi>who Ended lately the Days of his Warfare in</hi> France Here inſerted for Direction and Caution to as many as would understand, and Read with Profit, theſe enſuing Tracts.</head>
            <p n="1">1. THat which is the moſt Holy, the moſt Common, and the moſt Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary <hi>Exerciſe</hi> in the Spiritual Life, or Warfare, is the <hi>Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of GOD:</hi> It is to be pleas'd with, and to accuſtom our ſelves to his Divine Company, ſpeaking Humbly, and Lovingly Communing with HIM at all Times, in every Moment; without Rule or Meaſure; eſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cially in the time of Temptations, of Sufferings, of Aridities, of Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleaſures; and even of Unfaithfulneſſes and Falſeh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>od, that ſo we may immediately recover our ſelves.</p>
            <p n="2">2. We muſt continually endeavour that all our Actions, indifferently of what ſort ſoever, be a kind of little Conferences and Converſations with GOD; yet without Study, only as they proceed from the Purity and Singleneſs of Heart.</p>
            <p n="3">3. We muſt perform all our Actions with Weight and Meaſure; with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Impetuoſity or Precipitation, which denote a Wandring Spirit: We muſt Labour gently, quietly, and love-fully with GOD; muſt pray him to accept our Labour. And by this continual Attention to GOD we ſhall bruiſe the Head of the Devil, and ſhall make him to let fall his Arms.</p>
            <p n="4">4. We ought, during our Labour and other Actions, yea even in the midſt of our Reading and Writing, however Spiritual they may be; nay, moreover while we are at our Outward Devotions, and Vocal Prayers; to ceaſe and give over for a little Moment, and as frequently too as we can, to Worſhip GOD in the Center of our Heart, and to get a taſt of him, tho' by the By, and as it were by ſtealth. Since you are not igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant how GOD is preſent before you during your Actions, how he is in the Ground and Center of your Soul: Wherefore then it behoves you from time to time to retire and pauſe in the midſt of your Outward Occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pations, and alſo of your Vocal Prayers, to adore him inwardly, Praiſe him, Pray to him, offer him your Heart, and give him thanks.</p>
            <p n="5">5. All theſe Adorations are to be done through <hi>Faith,</hi> we believing of a Truth that GOD is <hi>in</hi> our Hearts; that he muſt be Worſhipped, Loved and Served <hi>in Spirit and Truth;</hi> that he ſeeth whatever cometh to paſs,
<pb facs="tcp:154251:9"/>and ſhall come to paſs in us, and in all the Creatures; that he is Independent from all, and that upon which all Created Beings depend; that he is In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>finite in all kind of Perfections, ſo as by his Infinite Excellency, and Soveraign Right of Dominion to deſerve all that we are, and all that is in Heaven and in Earth, whereof he may diſpoſe according to his Good Pleaſure both in Time and Eternity: And that conſequently we owe him in Juſtice all our Thoughts, Words, and Deeds.</p>
            <p n="6">6. We muſt carefully examine which are the Virtues that are moſt neceſſary for us; thoſe which are the moſt difficult to obtain; the Sins into which we are moſt apt to fall, and the moſt frequent and unavoidable Occaſions of our falling: We ought to have recourſe to GGD with an entire Faith and Confidence, while we are engag'd in the Combat, to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bide reſolute in the preſence of his Divine Majeſty, to Adore him in Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mility, to Repreſent to him our Miſeries and Weakneſſes, and to Beg affectionately the Aſſiſtance of his Grace, according to the ſeveral Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumſtances we are then under, and the ſtreſs of the Battel. This Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſation with GOD is in the Center of the Soul, where the Soul ſpeaks to GOD Heart to Heart, and always in a great and profound Peace, which it enjoys in GOD: And now all what paſſeth without is to the Soul no more than as a Fire of Straw, which is extinguiſh'd according to the Meaſure that the Holy Fire from Heaven is there enkindled; and cannot at all (or but very little) diſturb its Internal Peace.</p>
            <p>This is what was found Written by a Perſon, who had Practis'd for above Forty Years continually this Holy Exerciſe of the preſence of GOD, and of Communion with CHRIST in ſilence, by having his Converſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion in the Heavens, even amidſt all his External Employments: And who during Ten of theſe was Trained in the Battels of the <hi>Lamb,</hi> after ſuch a manner as is almoſt incredible; ſpecially to any that have not been in like manner Exercis'd, under the <hi>Fiery Proba</hi> (or Fire-Ordeal) that every true Chriſtian Soldier muſt paſs through of neceſſity. And they that will obtain the Garland of Roſes, in the Garden of <hi>Sharon,</hi> muſt (as he did) hold out in Fighting under the Banner of the Bleſſed Croſs of JESUS; till the Victory, preceeding the Firſt (and Spiritual) Reſurrection be obtain'd, and they can ſay that the LORD is riſen in them, by the Demonſtration of his (late) hidden Life, and that being in the Hands of GOD, they matter not what they do or ſuffer for him, and in Union with his Will: For this is to be their whole Buſineſs and Engagement. They muſt not be terrified at the Fire of the Cherub which guards the Paſſage, but muſt Valiantly break through the ſame in the Victorious Name of JESUS: whereby the Pretious Door of Pearl will be made to fly open, and a free entrance given into this Divine Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation, whither their Beloved is gone down to <hi>ſee the Fruits of the Valley,</hi> who will there eat his <hi>Honey-Comb</hi> with his Spouſe and Siſter: and will drink his <hi>Wine</hi> and his <hi>Milk</hi> with the Virgins of the Bride-Chamber, that ſhall have follow'd him fully in the proceſs of their Regeneration, and
<pb facs="tcp:154251:9"/>have trimmed their Lamps, filling them from the Seven Fountain-Lamps that burn perpetually before the Throne of the Majeſty, in the Light of which the Majeſty may be beheld in the Center and Ground of the Soul, as in its proper Mirrour and Reflection. And thus is that True and Spiritual Worſhip attained to, which this Holy Man did under many Outward and Heavy Burdens practiſe: and which he has thus, with all plainneſs and ſimplicity, expreſs'd in Declaring,
<list>
                  <item>1ſt. How that to Worſhip <hi>God <hi>in Spirit,</hi>
                     </hi> is to Worſhip him by an humble real Adoration of Spirit in the Center of our Souls: and that there is none but <hi>God</hi> who can ſee this Ado<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, which we may reiterate ſo often, till in the end it become as it were Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tural; and as if <hi>God</hi> were One with our Soul, and our Soul were One with <hi>God.</hi> Experience demonſtrates this.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>2dly,</hi> How to Worſhip <hi>God <hi>in Truth,</hi>
                     </hi> is to acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge him for what HE is, and to acknowledge our ſelves for what we are: How it is to own truly, actually, and in Spirit that <hi>God <hi>is That which HE IS,</hi>
                     </hi> that is, infinitely Perfect, infinitely Adorable, infinitely remov'd from Evil, <hi/> and to behave our ſelves ſuitably to ſuch an acknowledgement, under the Conduct of his Spirit.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>3dly,</hi> How to Worſhip <hi>God <hi>in Truth,</hi>
                     </hi> and under the Leading of the Spirit of Truth, is alſo to confeſs that we are entirely contrary to him, and that he is willing to make us Like unto himſelf: and how therefore it is a very great Folly for us to turn aſide but for one Moment from that Reſpect that Love, that Service, and thoſe continual Adorations which we owe to him.</item>
               </list> And there are not wanting at this Day many Worſhippers in the Spiritual Temple, who have well learnt theſe Divine Maxims, and have ſounded thereby a Mighty Alarm in a Neighbouring Kingdom: which may cauſe yet a greater Shaking than the Politi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cians are aware of, who will then be convinced too late (if they Repent not) no leſs of the Imprudence, than of the Injuſtice of thoſe Violent Meaſures which for ſome few Years paſt they have taken, in order to ſuppreſs the growth of this k<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd of Worſhip, (whoſe manifeſt Crime is that it is of no profit to the <hi>Merchants of Souls;</hi>) and will experiment the vain Attempt of thinking to Dam up a River that runs under Ground, and that may eaſily break forth in Seven Streams, while reſiſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in One. The Intereſt and Multitude that are engag'd on both ſides, are indeed moſt conſiderable: And the War that has been Proclaimed againſt theſe Spiritual Worſhippers in the inward Court is like to be yet of ſome Continuance, tho' pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecuted never ſo Vigorouſly. But theſe hear the Word of the LORD by his Prophets, ſaying unto them, <hi>Be not afraid, nor diſmayed by reaſon of this great Multitude; for the Battel is not Yours, but Gods: Ye ſhall not need to Fight in it your ſelves; only ſet your ſelves, ſtand ſtill, and ſee the Salvation of the LORD with (and in) you:</hi> And thus Believing in the LORD their God, by a continued Introverſion into the Divine Preſence, and a <hi>ſtanding ſtill</hi> in the Center and Fund of their Hearts, from all the Activity of their Corrupt Imaginations and Wills, that ſo the Pure Magia of the Holy Spirit may bring forth its Wonders; they ſhall ſurely be <hi>Eſtabliſh'd.</hi> But as for their Enemies, <hi>every one ſhall help to deſtroy ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther:</hi> Even as it was in the Great Day of the Valley of <hi>Berachah,</hi> ſo ſhall it be again. Wherefore every one that is of the Houſe of <hi>Judah</hi> (that is, they that are called to make a confeſſion of Spiritual Praiſe to the Divine Being as he is LOVE, and to acknowledge the Eternal duration of his <hi>Mercies;</hi>) and all the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants of <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> (that is, they that preſs after the Internal <hi>Quiet,</hi> and <hi>Reſt</hi> of the Soul;) and every one that is Liſted in the Military Roll of the <hi>Lamb of Mount-Sion</hi> (that is, they that are in the Election of <hi>God</hi> to the Firſt Reſurrecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, being Separated and Sanctified from the World to that end;) muſt above
<pb facs="tcp:154251:10"/>all things ſtudy this ſhort and eaſie Exerciſe of the Heavenly Militia, to ſtand in the preſence of <hi>God,</hi> and to ſtand ſtill: That ſo they may behold that great Salvation and Glory, which is now about to be revealed in theſe latter Ages of the World. But to be Maſters of this Holy Exerciſe, we are taught that there is required
<list>
                  <item>(1.) a Purity of Life very great:</item>
                  <item>(2.) a Faithfulneſs to the Practiſe of this Preſence, and to the Internal Beholding of <hi>God</hi> in the Light of Faith:</item>
                  <item>(3.) a particular Care that this Internal Beholding (tho' but for a Moment) may prevent, accompany, and end every Action that we undertake: And</item>
                  <item>(4.) O Obedience to the Spirit of Chriſt, to follow him whitherſoever he goeth, and to reſt where he reſteth; and eſpecially to obſerve this in the Reading of the Holy Scriptures, or other Books that are Written with any Degree of the Unction of this Bleſſed Spirit.</item>
               </list> And if Theſe, or any other Spiritual Treatiſes ſhall thus be begun to be Read by any, a proportionable Succeſs may thence be expected: and they will have no reaſon to complain of their Labour being loſt. There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſeek to learn this Holy Exerciſe here Deſcrib'd; then Read: So ſhall ye Underſtand, and ſo ſhall ye Profit. Otherwiſe there is nothing but may be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verted into Venom. Even the very <hi>Love of <hi>God</hi>
               </hi> it ſelf is at this Day become a Stumbling Block to many, as is well known: And if it be Pure from all Self-Intereſt, not ſeeking its Own but Gods, this alone we find is enough to raiſe the Jealouſie of the higheſt Eccleſiaſtical Princes and Courts. Whence as if there were danger of Loving <hi>God</hi> too much, or of ſeeking his Glory two Generouſly, the Paſſions of Men have been carried on againſt it to that Exorbitant Height (though ſtill under the faireſt Pretexts) as even to Decry it for turning Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtianity upſide down, as well as the World. Such is the blindneſs of Humane Nature, even in Good Men, as coming without that Preparation of Holy Silence which is requiſite, and without the Practiſe of that Exerciſe here recom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mended, we run into the groſſeſt miſtakes of Things and Perſons that are Spiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual. But if any one ſhall faithfully practiſe this Holy Exerciſe, and attend to the Preſence of <hi>God</hi> in his Soul, he ſhall be ſure to hear and underſtand that Heavenly Call, and Angelical Summons that is now beginning to go forth over the whole Earth, by Witneſſes raiſed up in all Parts, to Proclaim the Entrance of the <hi>Kingdom</hi> of <hi>Chriſt,</hi> in the Reſtitution of the Evangelical Spirit, and in the Renovation of Nature. And Thrice Bleſſed is he that ſhall be Obedient to this Call: For he ſhall have a Name Written upon the Foundations of the <hi>New Jeruſalem,</hi> and ſhall be made a Pillar in that Temple which deſcends from Heaven.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Fountain of Gardens,</hi> Vol. III. Part I. p. 151. <q>Theſe are thoſe that ſhall Fight the Battels of the LAMB, and bring him to Reign on (and over) the Earth: So that all Kingdoms and Nations may ſerve him as appearing in his Saints.</q>
            </p>
            <p>Iſa. 59.17, 19, 20. <hi>He put on Righteouſneſs as a Breaſt-plate, and an Hel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>met of Salvation upon his Head, and he put on the Garments of Vengeance for Cloathing, and was clad with Zeal as a Cloak. When the Enemy ſhall come in like a Flood, the SPIRIT of the LORD ſhall lift up a Standard againſt him: And the Redeemer ſhall come to</hi> Zion.</p>
            <p>Eph. 6.12, 13, 14. <hi>We wreſtle not againſt Fleſh and Blood, but against Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cipalities, againſt Powers, againſt the Rulers of the Darkneſs of this World, againſt Spiritual Wickedneſſes in high Places; wherefore take unto you the whole Armour of God, that ye may be able to withſtand in the</hi> Evil Day, <hi>&amp; having done all to ſtand. Stand therefore having your Loins girt about with Truth.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="table_of_contents">
            <pb facs="tcp:154251:10"/>
            <div n="1" type="treatise">
               <head>The CONTENTS of the Firſt Treatiſe.</head>
               <p>§. I. to V. A Signal Deliverance from the Angel of <hi>Death,</hi> being the Preparati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and Occaſion for the enſuing Divine Manifeſtation and Alarm; with what thereupon did follow, both for the Exerciſe and Encouragement of the Author's Faith. V. The ALARM. VI. The Manner of the Liſting, and Calling forth the Soldiers. VII. The <hi>Time</hi> of this Call. VIII. The <hi>Perſons</hi> made choice of. IX. The Kingdoms of <hi>David</hi> and <hi>Solomon</hi> Typical. X, XI, XII, XIII, XIV, XV, XVI. Motives for entring upon the Holy War. XVII. The Firſt En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gagement of the Holy Army. [<hi>Part.</hi> II.] XVIII, XIX. The General's Speech, and his Inſtructions to the Soldiers. XX, XXI, XXII, XXIII. The <hi>Alliance</hi> and Joining of the two Armies Superiour and Inferiour. XXIV. A Deſcription of the Deſcent of the Heavenly Watchers. XXV. The Third Watch ſet. XXVI. <hi>Rules</hi> preſcribed to the Watchers of the Inferiour Army. XXVII to XXXIV. <hi>Motives</hi> and Encouragements propos'd to them. XXXIV. An Univerſal Call to every one under Heaven, to prepare themſelves for the Kingdom of Chriſt, which is at hand. The <hi>Three</hi> Orders of them that are call'd. XXXV, XXXVI. The Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven Spirits, and Seven Rewards confer'd on thoſe of the Third Order. The Concluſion.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="treatise">
               <head>Of the Second Treatiſe.</head>
               <p>I. II. THE Manifeſtation of the <hi>Roſe of</hi> Sharon. III. The Multiplication of this Roſe: Or, the Garden of <hi>Sharon.</hi> IV. The Threefold Circle and Fence, about this Garden deſcribed. V. The Approach of this Beautiful and Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed State. VI. The Manner and Means of its Introduction. VII. The Paucity of its Number in which it will begin. VIII. IX. The Interpretation of the Twelve Leaves of this Roſe. X. The preſent Budding of this New Plantation. XI. The Glory and Excellency of Chriſt's Kingdom hence ariſing. XII. An Order to ſome Elect Perſons to Build the Walls of this Glorious Garden, with its Palace. XIII. A Deſcription of the Twelve Foundations thereof. XIV. The Qualifications of the Builders. XV. The Manner of their Incorporation. XVI. The Wonderful way of Communion betwixt all the Members of this Royal Corporation. XVII. Their Aſſemblies and Colledges, by a Perſonal gathering of the diſperſed Members. XVIII. Their manner of Life here, and their Redemption from the Earth. XIX. The Diſciplehood of <hi>Abraham</hi> Planted in this New Plantation. XX. The Renovation of the Paradiſical Life: And the Hidden Fraternity of the Roſe of <hi>Sharon.</hi> XXI. The Admiſſion of the Inhabitants to the Kings Preſence and Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour. XXII. The Separation required in all, to obtain this High Honour. XXIII. A needful Caution to all the Candidates that would be admitted into this New <hi>Sharon.</hi> XXIV. A General Invitation to all Perſons to accept and preſs after the ſame. [<hi>Part.</hi> II.] XXV. The Manifeſtation of <hi>Wiſdoms Cup.</hi> XXVI. A Particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Invitation to all the Inhabitants of this New Plantation, to drink of it. XXVII. An Interpretation of the Three ſeveral ſorts of Wine drunk out of it. And firſt of that which appertains to the <hi>Prieſtly</hi> Spirit. XXVIII. Of that which is appropriated to the <hi>Prophetical</hi> Spirit. XXIX. Of that which confers the <hi>Royal</hi> Spirit. XXX. The <hi>New Sharon</hi> further Deſcribed, its Seven Pools, and the Royal Honours and Prerogatives therein to be enjoyed. XXXI. The Miniſters of State that attend the Prince: their ſingular Wiſdom, and great Power. XXXII. Their Commiſſion to Proclaim the Time of the <hi>Lily.</hi> XXXIII. The Union of the Lily and the Roſe: and their Royal Generation thence produced. XXXIV. The Variety in Unity, and Unity in Variety within this Bleſſed Plantation. XXXV, XXXVI, XXXVII. The Concluſion, being an Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreſs to all ſorts of Perſons. The PRIZE. p. 19. A Conſiderable Relation ſent the Author, p. 22.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
